♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we've got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we'll reset it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko stronger after all ♪
Hey Einstein.
We’ve been looking everywhere for you.
I spent the whole night reading Franz Hopper’s diary.
Listen to this.
June 6th, 1994... day sixty-seven.
Project Carthage was a military program,
used to block enemy communications.
Wait, its further down.
So I built the super computer, created Lyoko,
and last of all, Xana, to destroy Carthage.
June 6th, 1994... day six-hundred thirty-nine.
It’s still further.
June 6th, 1994… day one-thousand, two-hundred, sixty-five.
Someone is watching me, someone wants to get rid of me.
(GASPS)
I wanted to destroy the supercomputer,
and destroy all the evidence of my activities.
That's when I discovered one of its fascinating properties.
Returning to the past.
It gave me all the time I could possibly need,
to perfect my great project
The only thing that would allow me to escape my enemies.
June 6th, 1994, day two thousand, five hundred, forty six.
This is it.
The scanners and virtualization programs are ready.
In a few hours, I will go to Lyoko with Aelita.
Just like me, Aelita will hold the keys to Lyoko.
Together, we will be the absolute masters,
We will live together, forever.
The keys to Lyoko, that’s what Xana wants to steal
From Aelita’s memory.
But what could Xana do with them?
Escape from the super computer,
and take over the world.
Aelita, you should have stuck around until the end.
I didn't have time to tell you the best news of all.
It turns out, I’ve been wrong all along.
You have? Why?
I thought that XANA had given Aelita a virus.
So I had been looking for an anti-virus.
But thanks to Franz Hopper’s diary, I finally understand.
Xana didn’t give her anything at all.
In fact, he took something from her.
He did, but what?
I don’t really know yet,
it’s a fragment that belongs to her.
I’ve located it in Sector Five.
We can go get it tonight.
After the end of the year dance.
Awesome! It’ll be our final mission.
Then it’s time for a well earned real vacation.
Out of the Question!
Huh?
Huh.
Aelita! Wait, what’s the matter?
I refuse to set foot on Lyoko ever again.
Why? Whats gotten into you.
My father stole my life from me.
He was a totally crazy second rate magician.
Because of him, I am nothing, I’m no one.
All of that’s behind you now.
We will recover the fragment that Xana took from you,
And shut down the supercomputer,
Then you will be free.
What if it goes wrong?
What if Xana gets the keys to Lyoko in my memory?
Right, for all you party animals, with short memory spans,
I would like to remind you that dah, what was I saying?
Oh yeah, uh, during the end of year dance,
Any overly suggestive dancing, wild behavior, or trouble making.
Will be severely punished.
Uh, thats all. Enjoy yourselves.
So far, I dont have anyone to take to the dance.
Fortunately, I got a way with women.
Hi, want do go to the dance with me?
I told you to never speak to me again!
Oh sorry.
Hey, who are you going with anyway?
Well, I was hoping to to talk to you about it.
Hi Yumi, can I talk to you for a second? I--
Ok, I get the idea now.
Yoo Hoo, what would you say,
To taking the prettiest girl in school to the dance?
Uh, you mean Anais Vieques?
No, she is going with Christopher Ambala.
I meant me, stupid. Well?
Uh, ok, I’ll go to the dance with you.
Uh?
Oh, re.. really? Uh, well, uh, great! See you tonight.
I’d rather look like a big loser, and go by--
--myself then go with someone like, like her.
Let it go Odd, ok.
Are you sure you won’t come to the dance with me?
Sure.
Are you going with another guy?
Hope so.
Oof, have you seen Aelita?
No.
There is no answer on her phone,
and the super computers not responding either.
Think its a bug?
Maybe. I’m going to the factory.
Cover for me with the teachers.
So Odd, did you find someone to take to the dance yet?
No.
Yoo hoo, Ulrich, here for you.
Yoo hoo, Ulrich!
What is it?
A surprise, see you tonight.
Ok, I get it.
What? You are going to the dance with William aren't you?
Is that a fact? Well, you really don’t get it do you?
Hmm.
One more of your stupid proverbs, and you are dead.
Ulrich has lost his head, and should have stayed in bed!
Wait wait, I’ve got another one!
Go with Sissi and your future’s gloomy,
cause your going to lose Yumi!
This isn’t right.
Aelita!
Aelita, answer me, come on! Wake up!
Ahh…
Your insane! Why did you do that?
To save the world, to save you all.
We’ll save it together,
and then you’ll have your whole life in front of you.
A brand new life!
You should get ready!
Your girlfriend’s going to be waiting for you.
Drop it Odd.
Ok, I’m out of here. Who knows?
Maybe I’ll bump into a lonely heart.
Is Yumi home?
Yumi! Your boyfriend’s here!
Beat it Hiroki!
Well then? Your not at the dance with Sissi?
I don't really like dancing, even less with Sissi.
Why are you here?
I came to tell you something.
(PHONE RINGING)
Aren't you going to get that?
Yes?
It’s me. You at the dance?
No, I don’t want to go.
Glad to hear it. Aelita and I aren’t going to go either.
Come to the factory, it’s mission time.
Let Odd and Yumi know too, ok?
Ok.
You-You, you haven’t seen Ulrich have you?
No, and he promised to take me to the dance.
Oh.
Hi, want to go to the dance with me?
Uh, alright, my name is Carla.
I’m Odd.
Odd Della Robbia?
The one and only.
I’m sorry, I’m already seeing someone.
Eh, oh.
(PHONE RINGING)
Odd, you at the dance?
Uh, yeah I uh, I mean almost.
Right, urgent meeting, come to the factory,
we’re taking the plunge.
Oh man, just when I finally almost found a girl to go with.
This is the big one guys.
We are going to recover Aelita’s fragment,
And get rid of Xana once and for all.
Let’s go then, I’ll lead the way.
Be careful.
Transfer Ulrich,
transfer Odd,
Virtualization!
Everybody alright?
Better than alright.
Transfer Yumi,
transfer Aelita.
I’m programming your vehicles too.
There you go. The edge of the sector is north, northeast.
No Monsters?
Nope
Don't you think that's weird?
Don't worry, Xana wasn’t expecting us.
Enter the code.
Ok, all aboard for Sector Five.
Oh.
What's wrong with you,
you feel like throwing up as usual?
No, I don’t, that’s what I can’t understand.
Everybody ready? I am going to enter the coordinates
of the room where Aelita’s fragment is.
Get ready, the wall is about to open.
You have three minutes to find the key and stop the countdown.
I see it.
Out of reach, as usual.
Look out!
Hi there creepers. Still as ugly as ever, huh?
Only one minute to go.
Yeah!
Supersprint!
Go for it Yumi.
Yumi, only ten seconds left! Hurry!
I’m almost there.
(GASP)
Nice job.
Want to see how low you can go huh guys?
I thought you were going to lead the way, go on.
Jeremie, there is something shining over there.
That’s it, that’s Aelita’s missing fragment.
Look out!
We better not hang around here.
Go on!
Jeremie, Yumi and Odd, are down.
I know, get Aelita’s fragment.
Huh?
The whole room is falling apart. Run for it!
Oh no!
(SCREAMING)
Jeremie, it’s getting worse.
Oh no, it’s getting better.
You’re crazy, what's going on?
Its Franz Hopper, who’s controlling the mantas.
This is amazing.
Huh?
It’s a trap!
Help me!
Aelita, behind you!
I don’t believe it.
There wasn’t anything I could do.
No!
(GASP)
Aelita’s… dead.
(ROAR x4)
What, what’s going on?
Xa-xana got what he wanted.
He has the keys to Lyoko.
He’ll be able to get out of the super computer.
(CRACKLING THUNDER)
Did you see mommy?
Don’t go too far sweetheart.
Oh, he’s so cute. What should I call him?
What about Mr. Puck? It means goblin.
Do you like him?
Oh thank you mommy.
It’s like math, let me show you.
♪ TWINKLE TWINKLE LITTLE STAR ♪
Mommy?
Daddy?
I’m going up to my room.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Alright, come out of there.
(GASP)
Daddy! The men in black are here.
I know, do you remember where Mr. Puck is?
Yes.
Come quickly.
(GASP)
This way.
There.
(GRUNTING)
But, where are we?
In my laboratory. Come on.
Where?
To a world, where we will be safe.
You and I, forever.
See you in a minute honey.
See you in a minute daddy.
(CELESTIAL HUMMING)
What’s going on Jeremy?
It’s Franz Hopper,
he’s bringing Lyoko back to life.
Look, it’s incredible
Franz Hopper is saving his daughter.
To the scanner room, quick!
Aelita!
Jeremie.
Right, would someone please say something funny,
before I have a heart attack?
My father sacrificed himself for me,
we don’t even know if he’s still on Lyoko.
Fine, excuse me while I have my heart attack.
All those memories of your life on Earth,
That was the fragment that Xana took from you.
To bind you to him.
And Franz Hopper managed to give them back to you.
Now your free Aelita,
but unfortunately, so is Xana.
Shutting the super computer down is not going to kill Xana anymore.
What are we going to do?
Same as always, we’ll fight.
Xana may have become more powerful.
But I don’t think he is invincible.
If he attacks, we’ll counter attack,
we will find a way to get rid of Xana for good.
And we will do everything we can to find your dad, Aelita.
You’re right, the fight has to go on.
After all, fighting Xana is my job.
No Aelita, it’s our job.
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY THE FOXTROT FANATICS